María Agustina La Rosa

Design Manager | Graphic Designer | UX/UI Designer | Web Developer

CONTACT INFORMATION

ma.agus.larosa@gmail.com

(571) 393-7120

Stuart, Florida.

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/agustinalarosa/

Bē https://www.behance.net/LaRosaMariaAgustina

SUMMARY

I started my journey as a visual communication designer because of my strong passion for visual graphics. I enjoy the challenge of translating a concept/idea into a visual message that represents a need that will be interpreted bythe targeted audience. During my nine years of experience, I have created strong relationships with multiple types of clients, learned about different fields, and developed multiple designs in between a few more things...

Looking now to put all my knowledge into practice by managing a creative team and ensuring every part of thedevelopment and creation process runs smoothly.

What I love to do:

- · Handle the production and processes of making a creative product.
- · Create action plans and use problem-solving methods to guide team members toward a finished product.
- Brainstorming concepts for a project.
- · Collaborate with other creative departments.
- · Meeting with clients and stakeholders to discuss needs.
- · Overseeing daily tasks.

EXPERIENCE

Design Manager

Icovy. Scottsdale, Arizona, United States.

Jan 2023 - Present

Responsible for managing the design and production of visual materials for print and digital media. Ensure that layout and design are aligned with brand and production standards and follow best practices.

- Lead creative development; collaborate with cross-functional teams, including copywriters and marketing managers, to develop visually compelling and scientifically accurate creative concepts for medical devices marketing campaigns and materials. Provide continual input to optimize design and minimize futile work, resulting in time and resource savings.
- Artistic direction; provide clear and concise artistic direction to other creative team members to ensure the highest quality standards are met in the creation of visuals and graphics.
- Maintain effective communication with stakeholders to provide project updates and address any potential issues or challenges. Participate in departmental strategic planning and assists technically with internal and external customers.
- Team leadership; guide and mentor the team, fostering a collaborative and high-performing work environment. Provide
 constructive feedback, and inspire creativity among team members. Develop team members through training and exposure
 to new job functions.
- Branding and visual identity; oversee multiple projects simultaneously, ensuring they meet the established creative objectives. Maintain and enhance the visual identity and branding guidelines across all marketing materials, ensuring consistency in messaging and visuals to strengthen brand recognition and brand equity. Create innovative ideas and designs and puts them into a context that the rest of the team and the client/customer can understand.
- Market and competitor research; stay updated on the latest trends, innovations, and best practices in marketing and design, conducting regular research to identify opportunities for improvement and differentiation.
- · Manage and maintain record keeping of original artwork files and all projects.

Marketing Graphic Designer

Icovy. Scottsdale, Arizona, United States. Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

Responsible for taking projects from concept to completion for internal teams and clients. Provide knowledge in front-end design and UX/UI methods for creative project deliverables and execution. Represent the company's brand and assist in driving creative strategies to increase product awareness by observing the market, competitors, and industry trends.

- Worked extensively with executive teams to develop creative needs for marketing campaigns and strategies to build and
 grow customer and internal brands. Helped articulate brand messages, positions, value proposition and processes with
 credibility and confidence to employees worldwide.
- Lead developer for social media, web, print collateral, ad design and other supporting projects. Utilized attention to detail and conceptual thinking skills to produce inspired visuals that responded to client goals and needs.
- · Conducted market research to stay ahead of market changes.
- Maintained effective communication with other team members updating them on project status in order to successfully manage time between client and internal projects to meet deadlines.

Freelance Graphic Designer

Continuum Clinical. Northbrook, Illinois, United States.

Dec 2021 - Jan 2022

Lead the development of design collateral based on existing concepts, including, but not limited to, retail POP, logos, various print collateral, and a variety of digital elements.

Graphic Designer

3 Comunicaciones Estrategicas. Comodoro Rivadavia, Chubut, Argentina.

Feb 2020 - Nov 2020

Responsible for creating visual communications that resonate with a specific target audience for multiple customer accounts. Primary customers were Penta Medical Studies Center, Urbana Higiene Ambiental, and other local entities.

- Continuously communicated with coworkers regarding order status and project completion. Responsible for refining project details and monitoring changes requested by the customer.
- Developed, scheduled, and reported activities and projects completed every week to keep track of hours worked and the company budget balanced.
- Created multiple visual communication design pieces such as posters, brochures, covers, cards, merchandising, and advertisements to meet customer needs.
- · Provided guidance, consultation, and assistance to coworkers in regard to graphic design work.
- · Used multiple types of graphic design software to help form and implement graphic designs for the company and customers
- Created, maintained, and updated content for customer social media accounts.

Account Executive

3 Comunicaciones Estrategicas. Comodoro Rivadavia, Chubut, Argentina. Jun 2016 - Aug 2017

Account Executive and Communications Consultant responsible for managing and overseeing multiple customer accounts and projects. Maintained direct contact with the customers for the company to receive and manage all work orders. Created and presented original graphic designs for customers that were used for corporate communication, advertisements and events. Prepared digital presentations for customers to show client increase, growth, conclusions and results of advertising campaigns. Developed and implemented new sales and communications strategies that greatly increased the productivity of the customers' companies.

- Researched and provided updated quotes; reviewed pricing catalogues and contacted vendors to obtain pricing estimates
 for various products and graphic design projects. Hired and managed outside professionals that helped create the
 customer products.
- Supervised multiple projects; worked closely with the customer and the coworkers to ensure the projects met their
 deadlines. Provided estimated material costs for each project and ensured the company stayed within the customer's
 budget. Maintained authority for determining and establishing the priority for which projects and customer orders needed
 to be created. Communicated with stakeholders to refine details and make the necessary changes. Reported the customer
 activities and projects completed every month to keep track of hours worked and maintain accurate balanced budgets.

- Used multiple types of software and current creative methods to help design and implement graphic designs for the company and customers. Determined which digital medium was the most appropriate for the production and promotion of the desired visual effect, as well as the best means of communication.
- Vendor and agency management; Collaborate with external agencies and vendors to select, brief, and manage third-party suppliers when necessary, ensuring their deliverables align with project requirements and meet quality standards.
 Cultivated and maintained relationships with influential people in the media. Attended multiple events in order to maintain relationships with influential people and the customers.
- Maintained the customers' social media accounts. Created content for company websites, social networks and maintained online contact with their consumers.

Graphic Designer

Shopping Del Sur. Comodoro Rivadavia, Chubut, Argentina Jan 2014 – Jul 2016

Responsible for the graphic arts and visual materials section of this major Furniture store. Designed and implemented graphic designs in order to attract more customers.

- Designed and created multiple brochures, logos, magazines, and vinyl for the store that increased the business of the store and brought in new customers.
- Created weekly advertisements for the store to be published in the local newspaper.
- Managed the store's social media account and website. Responsible for all ads, content creation, and updates that were posted to the digital media accounts. Content updates included pricing, discounts, and the introduction of new products.

Freelance Graphic Designer

Infinito. Comodoro Rivadavia, Chubut, Argentina.

Feb 2016 - May 2016

Freelance Graphic Designer responsible for designing and creating visual concepts using computer software. Created designs for the customer that inspired, informed, and captivated their consumers.

- · Conceptualized and implemented new designs for marketing materials and ads.
- Prepared and produced final artwork for customers.
- Used multiple types of software to created designs while collaborating with clients to determine their visual needs and targeted audience.
- · Provided a variety of visual aids and graphics for clients to have multiple options to select from for their advertisements.
- Developed the overall layout designs for advertisements, brochures, posters, menus and logos for renowned restaurants, stores, and companies.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

- Bachelor's Degree, Visual Communication Design. La Plata National University, December 2015
- UX/UI Design Certification. Coder House, October 2021
- Advance UX/UI Design Certification. Coder House, August 2022
- Project Manager. Coder House, February 2023
- Webflow Experts. Webflow, April 2023
- Web Development. Coder House, October 2023

TOOLS

Adobe llustrator
 Adobe InDesign
 Adobe Photoshop
 Figma
 Webflow
 SharePoint
 Google Drive
 Google Slide
 Stripo
 Visual Studio

Adobe Lightroom
 Asana
 Microsoft Office